<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devops on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </title>
    <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/categories/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devops on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tolleiv&#34;&gt;tolleiv&lt;/a&gt; 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Powered by Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 22:18:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.tolleiv.de/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Post mortem documentations or how to build knowledge during failures</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/01/post-mortem-documentations-or-how-to-build-knowledge-during-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 22:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/01/post-mortem-documentations-or-how-to-build-knowledge-during-failures/</guid>
      <description>Few months ago I tried to get my head around Post-Mortem documentations and found it particularly hard to fill the gap between the publicly available documentations and my aim to have company internal documentations which teams could use to share knowledge and learn from past mistakes. During my research I came across lot’s of publicly available information which helped me to dive into the topic. But unfortunately information was widely distributed and I though that sharing my link collection could help to shorten your way a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef cookbook dependecy visualization</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/07/chef-cookbook-dependecy-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 15:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/07/chef-cookbook-dependecy-visualization/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out some tools which make your live with Chef much easier. Among these, Berkshelf helps with managing cookbooks and their dependencies. Depending on your workflows these can be very straight forward or grow very complex.
I had some free time and thought that visualizing these dependencies as graphs could be a fun weekend project. You can test out the results on berksgraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef QA toolchain</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/chef-qa-toolchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/chef-qa-toolchain/</guid>
      <description>In the past years I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped into the role of the DevOps evangelist at AOE. As it seems this was quite successful and people joined in quickly. But due to the fact that DevOps for us also means that less trained colleges should participate in most parts of the codified infrastructure, it requires some quality assurance efforts in the background. An overview of the tools which help us to keep things clean, is what I wanted to share in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>