<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Offtopic on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </title>
    <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/categories/offtopic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Offtopic on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tolleiv&#34;&gt;tolleiv&lt;/a&gt; 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Powered by Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 17:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.tolleiv.de/categories/offtopic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from home.</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/working-from-home./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/working-from-home./</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s so much work in this week that I can&amp;rsquo;t publish a article in the next days.
But Natalie Jost from A List Apart just published a very nice article which you really should read if you&amp;rsquo;re (like me) working from home read on.. &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>track time for a subroutine within a shell-script</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/track-time-for-a-subroutine-within-a-shell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/track-time-for-a-subroutine-within-a-shell-script/</guid>
      <description>The following code-snippet is a shell-script which does the following:
 Track the time for a block of shell commands
 Check if the time was less than x seconds (the example uses 10 seconds)
 If the block run through too fast the script waits/sleeps a few seconds
 Run all this within a loop so that the block of shell-commands is executed periodically
  I used the script combined with a PHP script which processes a queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YSlow - powerful FF extension</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/yslow---powerful-ff-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/yslow---powerful-ff-extension/</guid>
      <description>I use firebug for a while and I love it especially for CSS and JS debugging. Today I stumbled over Yslow and did some tests with it one some of my clients pages and I love the results.
YSlow can help you to analyze all the referenced elements on a webpage. It shows their sizes, how they behave when a page is taken from the browser-cache, shows optimization hints and enables a easy way to optimize the output of your dynamically created webpage :) &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP FastCGI vs. PHP as a module</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-fastcgi-vs.-php-as-a-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-fastcgi-vs.-php-as-a-module/</guid>
      <description>The apachelounge.org guy published a very interesting stat which compares the memory-usage of PHP/FastCGI and PHP/as module and that&amp;rsquo;s really interesting:

There&amp;rsquo;s no comment about performance and in early versions FastCGI/PHP was a bottleneck but maybe these days are gone :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 3 RC1</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/firefox-3-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/firefox-3-rc1/</guid>
      <description>I just saw that the first Release Candidate of Firefox 3 is available for download . As with the most of the Beta-versions I also checked this update because I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get the new features, but after 5 minutes (again) I removed it from my PC. Non of my extensions is working in FF3 (except the dictionary), it still destroys the Frames in TYPO3 (there&amp;rsquo;s a bugfix-extension for that) and the memory-usage is still very high,10% lower than in FF2 but still high.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>