<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog.tolleiv.de ...  </title>
    <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/tags/design/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tolleiv&#34;&gt;tolleiv&lt;/a&gt; 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Powered by Hugo</copyright>
    <atom:link href="//blog.tolleiv.de/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>webdesign and stuff that came along my way today</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine recommended this URL in regards to one topic which I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2009/03/24/designing-drop-down-menus-examples-and-best-practices/&#34;&gt;Designing Drop-Down Menus: Examples and Best Practices &lt;/a&gt;. This article about how to use Drop-Down menus within the navigation, including some DOs and some DONTs,  is a very nice summary for anyone who creates designs with these elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I scanned that article, I found another one which will be my default answer in the future whenever clients or coworkers ask strange questions about features and designs: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2009/02/18/9-common-usability-blunders/&#34;&gt;9 Common Usability Mistakes In Web Design | How-To | Smashing Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. There are lot&amp;rsquo;s of lists around in the Web but there aren&amp;rsquo;t so many sources with this quality and with such an amount of good quality comments in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also discovered a new TYPO3 extension which will be imho very popular in the future - check it out yourself - &lt;a href=&#34;http://typo3.org/extensions/repository/view/canonical/&#34;&gt;canonical extension in TER&lt;/a&gt;. Regarding the TER I also found this &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.zikula.org/module-Extensions-display-ot-component-componentid-37.htm&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; some days ago within the newsgroups and I like to idea of having this for TYPO3 -I wonder whether this will stay a dream :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally I just caught up with my RSS reader and the last article was the most interesting for today, since it is written from a different perspective (type-designer perspective) and it&amp;rsquo;s really interesting how he images the future for fonts in the web. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/realfontsontheweb&#34;&gt;Interview with David Berlow&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>