<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </title>
    <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tolleiv&#34;&gt;tolleiv&lt;/a&gt; 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Powered by Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:10:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.tolleiv.de/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookmarks to followup on in Oktober</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2016/11/bookmarks-to-followup-on-in-oktober/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 20:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2016/11/bookmarks-to-followup-on-in-oktober/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of things I bookmarked last month which I found worth sharing. There are lot of Kubernetes related articles among them as this is my area of interest for me at the moment.
 Why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t trust successful people&amp;rsquo;s advice  on www.youtube.com Why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t trust successful people&amp;rsquo;s advice, at least not without looking left and right too. Time invest: 5min The misunderstood Docker tag: latest by Marc Campbell on medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another blogging software migration</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2016/11/another-blogging-software-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 21:15:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2016/11/another-blogging-software-migration/</guid>
      <description>After I switched to Octopress, I ran into a bunch of issues which kept me from publishing more often. One of the main issues was the ongoing struggle with the publishing workflow itself (you see it&amp;rsquo;s not my fault but the tools). In the past days I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to Hugo and implemented an automated publishing workflow with travis-ci. The content migration itself wasn&amp;rsquo;t too impressive, using hugo import jekyll .. did all the magic for me :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enrich Zabbix monitoring with additional data from Pingdom</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/11/enrich-zabbix-monitoring-with-additional-data-from-pingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 08:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/11/enrich-zabbix-monitoring-with-additional-data-from-pingdom/</guid>
      <description>If you’re running your own monitoring system which has to observe services for global customers, you might have considered to spin up some monitoring slaves around the world to gather accurate availability data. Unfortunately bringing up these slaves is time consuming and expensive to some extend. On the other hand services like Pingdom provide global monitoring for low budget. But using these splits your monitoring infrastructure into two parts and brings drawbacks when it comes to reporting and alerting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post mortem documentations or how to build knowledge during failures</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/01/post-mortem-documentations-or-how-to-build-knowledge-during-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 22:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2015/01/post-mortem-documentations-or-how-to-build-knowledge-during-failures/</guid>
      <description>Few months ago I tried to get my head around Post-Mortem documentations and found it particularly hard to fill the gap between the publicly available documentations and my aim to have company internal documentations which teams could use to share knowledge and learn from past mistakes. During my research I came across lot’s of publicly available information which helped me to dive into the topic. But unfortunately information was widely distributed and I though that sharing my link collection could help to shorten your way a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef cookbook dependecy visualization</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/07/chef-cookbook-dependecy-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2014 15:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/07/chef-cookbook-dependecy-visualization/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve pointed out some tools which make your live with Chef much easier. Among these, Berkshelf helps with managing cookbooks and their dependencies. Depending on your workflows these can be very straight forward or grow very complex.
I had some free time and thought that visualizing these dependencies as graphs could be a fun weekend project. You can test out the results on berksgraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chef QA toolchain</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/chef-qa-toolchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/chef-qa-toolchain/</guid>
      <description>In the past years I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped into the role of the DevOps evangelist at AOE. As it seems this was quite successful and people joined in quickly. But due to the fact that DevOps for us also means that less trained colleges should participate in most parts of the codified infrastructure, it requires some quality assurance efforts in the background. An overview of the tools which help us to keep things clean, is what I wanted to share in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socket.IO within concurrent processes</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/socket.io-within-concurrent-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 15:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/socket.io-within-concurrent-processes/</guid>
      <description>The following is going to show some pitfalls and their solution when working with NodeJs, Socket.IO and concurrent processes.
Basic setup Socket connections In order to use socket communication with NodeJS a basic server side code block might look this see online docs:
var io = require(&#39;socket.io&#39;).listen(80); io.sockets.on(&#39;connection&#39;, function (socket) { socket.emit(&#39;news&#39;, { hello: &#39;world&#39; }); });  This enables you to send some data through the socket connection to the client and with just a little more code it could even retrieve some data from the client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Octopress migration</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/octopress-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 09:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2014/05/octopress-migration/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally managed to step away from Wordpress and migrated my blog to Octopress. There were many reasons for me, the main reason was that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to host it by myself anymore.
The migration itself was guided by some blog posts which helped me a lot to get insights into Octopress:
 Migrating 40,000 Posts From Wordpress to Octopress Octopress SEO and Disabling the Blog Route Custom Domain With Octopress and Github Pages Create Custom Rss Feed for Octopress Add Flattr to Octopress  Besides that I managed to keep all the old URLs and migrated the comments to Diqus which went pretty smooth with very little configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila - followup</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/templavoila---followup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 09:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/templavoila---followup/</guid>
      <description>It seems that publishing the news regarding TemplaVoila came to the right time and it found its way through the community. But along with it, some irritation came up which needs some additional words.
Will there be a TYPO3 CMS 6.2 compatible version of TemplaVoila? **As it seems: yes - **some members of the community offered their help. I&amp;rsquo;ll reach out to them in the next days and try to connect them as good as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila future</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/templavoila-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 07:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/templavoila-future/</guid>
      <description>If you followed some of my comments in the TYPO3 newsgroups recently, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard that I&amp;rsquo;m not very satisfied with the TYPO3 project in general and that&amp;rsquo;s also reflected in my activity for TemplaVoila. After a certain time of inactivity I even had to ask myself whether it&amp;rsquo;s wort to keep it in the TYPO3 universe or not. Due to the fact that this isn&amp;rsquo;t an easy decision, I created a pro and con list which I&amp;rsquo;d like to share, before I make conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using genetic algorithms to optimize Apache Solr boost factors.</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/using-genetic-algorithms-to-optimize-apache-solr-boost-factors./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 18:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2013/06/using-genetic-algorithms-to-optimize-apache-solr-boost-factors./</guid>
      <description>Configuration interface.One thing I took along from last year&amp;rsquo;s ApacheCon was the idea to combine Apache Solr along with some mathematical search algorithms to figure out boost factor values. I did some work on that back then and on the way to this year&amp;rsquo;s BerlinBuzzwords. Now I finally have a proof-of-concept working which I&amp;rsquo;d like to share. If you want to have a look right away - the code can be found on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: How to move on? #TYPO3</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/re-how-to-move-on-#typo3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 09:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/re-how-to-move-on-#typo3/</guid>
      <description>As I wanted to answer Robert&amp;rsquo;s post but didn&amp;rsquo;t like the privacy of our Core-internal list, here&amp;rsquo;s some kind of response to it. Alongside I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain the current situation and problems a bit***.
What happend? In his post Robert kind of gave up his attempts to establish a TYPO3 product board [1]. The reasons for this are very wide-spread and mainly the various flame-wars in the last year and the very personal attacts brought him to the conclusion to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 login state and Varnish cache</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/typo3-login-state-and-varnish-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 15:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/typo3-login-state-and-varnish-cache/</guid>
      <description>Caching is hard in complex page setups with user specific content, especially when public pages change their content once a user is logged in. TYPO3 is smart enough to deal with the login state properly and cache appropriately. Once Varnish is involved, it&amp;rsquo;s quite tricky to cache as much as possible without loosing the dynamic content. But it&amp;rsquo;s not impossible and here&amp;rsquo;s my summary how we resolved it for typo3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding TypoScript errors.</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/02/finding-typoscript-errors./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 16:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/02/finding-typoscript-errors./</guid>
      <description>When you work on TypoScript templates in TYPO3, errors might show up in the TypoScript Object Browser. Within the error messages you&amp;rsquo;ll see a more or less detailed error description with the related line number. Within most setups these line numbers won&amp;rsquo;t relate to any of your sys_template records or TypoScript files directly. But they still provide value if you know how they help to find the right spot. As it&amp;rsquo;s not too obvious how to find the right spot I&amp;rsquo;ve created a little screenshot series to guide you to the broken spots in your templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing TYPO3 Core activity</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/visualizing-typo3-core-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/visualizing-typo3-core-activity/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: Don&amp;rsquo;t take the following too serious - when reading this post please keep in mind that the TYPO3 community itself consists of much more than just the Core team activity - many things take place outside of code repositories and can&amp;rsquo;t be measured anyhow. Every contribution is important and every single action has value.
 Using Gerrit sometimes feels quite lonesome - you don&amp;rsquo;t really see who&amp;rsquo;s active and you don&amp;rsquo;t really get a feeling on how much is done in the TYPO3 Core at a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.6.x</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/templavoila-1.6.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 07:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/templavoila-1.6.x/</guid>
      <description>Quite some things changed in the past months and I never found the time to clear up my mind and write up a summary.
First of all TemplaVoila 1.6 was released parallel to TYPO3 4.6. It shipped with 22 bug and compatibility fixes. In general the 1.6.x branch is supposed to be compatible with TYPO3 4.4+ which also made it possible to clean up the extension quite a bit. In addition to that TemplaVoila 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further reading 2011</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/further-reading-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 10:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/further-reading-2011/</guid>
      <description>Holiday time is usually a great opportunity to take time for things which didn&amp;rsquo;t really fit into the passed by year and to pick up things which help me to see beyond my nose. Along with some paper work and some house work there&amp;rsquo;s quite a list of programming related things I read and tried during the last days. And to give you some inspiration here&amp;rsquo;s my list:
 The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master - a must read for every programmer and once in a while worth to take a look at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging page caches</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/tagging-page-caches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 17:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/tagging-page-caches/</guid>
      <description>In our small TYPO3 world it&amp;rsquo;s quite common to have list and single views for extensions on specific pages. That&amp;rsquo;s quite nice because once a record is changed it allowes users to flush the caches for these pages automatically, using:
TCEMAIN.clearCacheCmd=all|&amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;  But of course it isn&amp;rsquo;t very smart to clear all caches once you have filled them up for hundred or even thousand records. To work around these limits it&amp;rsquo;s quite handy to use an API which lives in TYPO3 since 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal / Slots in Extbase</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/11/signal-/-slots-in-extbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 17:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/11/signal-/-slots-in-extbase/</guid>
      <description>A nice thing to have at hand is definately Signal and Slots. I heard Felix talking about them quite often and I finally found a nice usecase and came to play with them a little bit this afternoon. And just to avoid that others have to look around too much to find how they can get them to work here&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s working for me.
First of all you should understand the concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release reviews (templavoila, imagemap_wizard, workspaces)</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/02/release-reviews-templavoila-imagemap_wizard-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 21:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/02/release-reviews-templavoila-imagemap_wizard-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>I just push the TER upload button two times and in addition to that TYPO3 4.5.2 will be released tomorrow containing some nice workspaces updates. So here&amp;rsquo;s a short summary what happened in the extension releases.
TemplaVoila 1.5.4 The current release focussed on 4.5 compatibility. It uses the new sys_language flag &amp;ldquo;format&amp;rdquo; to support sprites, it hooks into the new backend-form (TCA) &amp;ldquo;layout&amp;rdquo; and add&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s fields to the right tabs within the backend forms and adjusts everything to work fine with the new CSRF mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 4.5 beta1</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/11/typo3-4.5-beta1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 21:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/11/typo3-4.5-beta1/</guid>
      <description>As announced on news.typo3.org yesterday the TYPO3 Core team published TYPO3 4.5 beta. With this beta the features for the next version are fixed and the remaining time until the release will be used for polishing and bug fixing. A complete list of the included features and changes can be found on forge.typo3.org.
As member of the TYPO3 workspace team I&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage everyone to send as much feedback as possible for all the workspace related changes and since maintaining TemplaVoila is also still on my list, it would be great if you let me know if you find any TemplaVoila related issues with the new TYPO3 version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.5 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/10/templavoila-1.5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 20:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/10/templavoila-1.5-released/</guid>
      <description>The new version comes with many bugfixes,new features and a closer TYPO3 integration. Overall 95 issues have been resolved in the last 4 months to finalize this versions, some of the highlights are:
HTML5 support The full list of HTML5 tags is now supported in TemplaVoila. The restrictions to specific tags was removed and the TYPO3 integrator is now able to use the full bandwidth of modern HTML. With this change also the tag-icons themself were replaced and the coloring schema was changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila on github.com</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/09/templavoila-on-github.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 15:52:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/09/templavoila-on-github.com/</guid>
      <description>Update: Finally TemplaVoila moved to git.typo3.org - please read the update here
 As it seems, souce code version control for TYPO3 will be done with Git in the future. The Phoenix team already uses git.typo3.org, there&amp;rsquo;s also already the possibility to get the latest updates for the v4 Core via github.com and it won&amp;rsquo;t take long until git.typo3.org is been used for version 4 as well.
Due to the fact that my TemplaVoila development workflow is also already git based, I thought it might be interesting for some contributors to develop with a git repository upstream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Sunde talking about flattr</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/08/peter-sunde-talking-about-flattr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 15:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/08/peter-sunde-talking-about-flattr/</guid>
      <description>Markus Beckedahl&amp;rsquo;s interview with Peter Sunde brought up some interesting insights into the system of flattr.com and the idea behind it. So if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in flattr.com you should listen the podcast on netzpolitik.org.
My favorite quote:&amp;ldquo;In the end stupid stuff founds good stuff&amp;rdquo; P. Sunde
Another (shorter) interview taken during the Hacknight in Malmö can be found on nrli.tv</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 4.4 sprites in your extension...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/typo3-4.4-sprites-in-your-extension.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/typo3-4.4-sprites-in-your-extension.../</guid>
      <description>TYPO3 4.4 ships with a long list of improvements. One of them is the sprite API which was developed during T3UXW09. It extends the iconWorks API and enables to retrieve any backend-icon from a central sprite.
As extension maintainer there are several ways to use these new parts of the API you can either just use it to display core icons, you can include your own icons and retrieve it with the new API or you can include your own sprite and retrieve the separate icons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3DD10 Git workshop</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/t3dd10-git-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 22:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/t3dd10-git-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I just found that Peter shares the slides of the Git workshop from the T3DD10 on slideshare. Since this 4 hour workshop was - for many reasons - one of my favorites during the T3DD10, I felt that it&amp;rsquo;s worth to mention it. And due to the fact that TYPO3 is moving very fast towards Git it&amp;rsquo;s worth to look at them ;) &amp;mdash; Open workshop slides
Btw. at the beginning I didn&amp;rsquo;t belief that a Git workshop could fill 4 hours - now I don&amp;rsquo;t think that shorter workshops make any sense :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git svn for TYPO3 extension development</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/using-git-svn-for-typo3-extension-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/using-git-svn-for-typo3-extension-development/</guid>
      <description>When I first saw a presentation about Git 2 years ago I liked it, but I was convinced that Subversion covers all I need. Things have changed and especially the bad performance of Subversion for larger repositories and the need to commit things without messing up the official trunk motivated me to look up how to get started with Git. If you need more reasons why you should look into Git, you&amp;rsquo;ll find them in [7] - anyways it&amp;rsquo;s worth to have a look how I managed to work with it ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 workspaces</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/typo3-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 17:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/typo3-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>One of the enterprise features TYPO3 has to offer is versioning and workspace handling. Kasper did a great job when he initially brough these featues into TYPO3. Unfortunately during the last years they became orphans and nobody really took care of them. There are multiple reasons for that, one was that Kasper didn&amp;rsquo;t allow big changes, another one was that everyone was somehow able to live with the existing odds they had but probable the most important one was that it was just to complicated to improve them alone without knowing the big picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tiny update...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/05/tiny-update.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 16:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/05/tiny-update.../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty busy in these days and unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s not much time to write blogposts. In detail there&amp;rsquo;s currently a long list of feature wishes and bugs for TemplaVoila which need my attention and in addition I also already started to prepare a workshop for the T3DD10 about Git*.
Just to keep this blog alive this is what I found interesting during the last weeks:
For TYPO3 enthusiasts especially the changes within the TYPO3 Core regarding the integration of further T3UX09 results and all the small changes which happen to get 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crawler 3.1 release &#43; podcast</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/crawler-3.1-release---podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 22:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/crawler-3.1-release---podcast/</guid>
      <description>Nearly a month after version 3.0.5, we published 3.1.0 of the well known crawler extension today. The main work for that step was related to several bugfixes, a better scheduler integration, some CLI-API enhancements, better testcases and (finally) some documentation updates. Most kudos go to Michael Klapper who took over the responsibility for this release and who also fixed a decent amount of bugs. You can download the extension in the TER  and hopefully this time OpenOffice didn&amp;rsquo;t trick us again and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see a shiny new extension manual on typo3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.4.2 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/templavoila-1.4.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 23:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/templavoila-1.4.2-released/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the 2nd team release of TemplaVoila was uploaded into the TER. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a maintenance release which fixes more than 100 bugs. But since we haven&amp;rsquo;t been that straight distinguishing between bug and usability feature, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a couple of new things within this release.
The high level release notes are:
 page module is now customizable with CSS and JavaScript
 handling of static data structures are improved and fully working now</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Farewell, TemplaVoila!</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/re-farewell-templavoila/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 23:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/re-farewell-templavoila/</guid>
      <description>Dmitry decided to leave the TemplaVoilà project today and he handed the extension-leadership to me. Since this is a very abrupt change and since there was lot&amp;rsquo;s of (mis)communication involved I&amp;rsquo;d like to use this blogpost to answer his &amp;ldquo;Farewell, TemplaVoila!&amp;rdquo; post (he turned off the commenting function).
As you might know Steffen Kamper and I joined the TemplaVoilà team some time ago and since Dmitry wasn&amp;rsquo;t very motivated to maintain the extension anymore, we took over and tried to make TemplaVoilà ready for TYPO3 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling data in TYPO3 with tcemain</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/handling-data-in-typo3-with-tcemain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 07:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/handling-data-in-typo3-with-tcemain/</guid>
      <description>TYPO3 is (by definition) a powerful tool when it comes to data. Besides creating, updating and deleting data there are also localizing and versioning, logging and even rollbacks. All this is provided through the GUI of TYPO3 and all the technical stuff in working under the hood of TYPO3 for nearly every piece of data. But what if you&amp;rsquo;re asked to write a script which imports or updates data, how can you make sure that all this is done in a TYPO3 compatible way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crawler extension version 3.0.5 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/02/crawler-extension-version-3.0.5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 15:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/02/crawler-extension-version-3.0.5-released/</guid>
      <description>Quite some time after the 4.3 release of TYPO3, we published the necessary compatibility version of the crawler extension. Besides the compatibility fixes for TYPO3 and also for PHP 5.3 we also included some handy features:
First of all there&amp;rsquo;s now, besides the CLI interface, also a full integration with the scheduler extension, which is available in TYPO3 4.3. This enables to setup crawler runs and manage all crawler releated tasks through the TYPO3 backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging mod_rewrite... my favorite way</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/01/debugging-mod_rewrite...-my-favorite-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 17:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/01/debugging-mod_rewrite...-my-favorite-way/</guid>
      <description>Once a month someone is asking because he has issues to get his mod_rewrite rules to do what he want&amp;rsquo;s. Writing the rules and the required RegEx for these rules is quite easy, but Apache still behaves strange every now and then and that&amp;rsquo;s where one of my favorite ways to &amp;ldquo;debug&amp;rdquo; mod_rewrite comes in very handy. And I felt that writing something is better than having a silent blog ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 4.3 release</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/typo3-4.3-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 18:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/typo3-4.3-release/</guid>
      <description>Today the TYPO3 Core Team released version 4.3 (release-notes on typo3.org).
Finally the list of improvements is long and the amount of cool new features is outstanding compared to other releases. Imho especially the security and performance-improvements are remarkable as well as the improved usability in the backend. But I guess my favorite improvement is obvious (hint hint) :P
In addition to TYPO3 4.3 a new major version of the tt_news (ter) extension was released over the weekend (Rupert Germans announcement on lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.4 released...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/templavoila-1.4-released.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/templavoila-1.4-released.../</guid>
      <description>A new version of TemplaVoila (ter) (forge) has just been released. Besides the great fact that this is the first team-release of TemplaVoila, the high-level improvements within the pagemodule (drag&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;drop), the mapping module and the FCE editing forms and besides lot&amp;rsquo;s of bug fixes, there are a few very nice features which make the day-to-day work with TemplaVoila much easier.
The list of things which happend in 1.4 can be seen on bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 Core Changelog feeded</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/typo3-core-changelog-feeded/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 20:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/typo3-core-changelog-feeded/</guid>
      <description>It seems that the newsgroup is a nice tool for the discussion but not to keep track of the actual changes -To get an idea of what actually happend at the code-base usually you might want to look at the ChangeLog. Therefore I had a script which converted the ChangeLog to an atom feed - a couple of colleagues liked this idea and asked me to publish it - so here it is: http://feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>imagemap_wizard 0.5.3</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/imagemap_wizard-0.5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 19:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/imagemap_wizard-0.5.3/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I&amp;rsquo;ve released the first official stable version of my imagemap_wizard extension (TER). I though that&amp;rsquo;s a good moment to review the introduction text on the project-homepage and that&amp;rsquo;s how it looks like - forge.typo3.org/projects/show/extension-imagemap_wizard
Especially due to the missing/broken TER download counter I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure whether the work was worth it. I hope some marketing and the given information about all the cool featutes is enough for newbees and TYPO3 pro&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting UK</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/visiting-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 20:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/visiting-uk/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on vacation over the last days and due to the fact that the time together with Heiner and Norman was great I wanted to write something meaningful - but I&amp;rsquo;m not a good writer when it comes to non technical stuff and therefore that&amp;rsquo;s what happend: Altenburg, RyanAir, Boeing 737 , Great Britain, Pound sterlin, Stansted, London, Tube, CCTV, Kings Cross, Hostel, St. Pancras, Pizza, Pub, Beerhouse Act, Pint, Bunk bed, Cereals, Watterloo station, London Eye, Shell game, House of Parliament, Big Ben, Westminster Abbey, Churchill, St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 crawler extension</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/09/typo3-crawler-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 07:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/09/typo3-crawler-extension/</guid>
      <description>Cool thing just happend after a couple of months we finally released the new version of the famous crawler extension. Read more on forge,typo3.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>multiple arguments for mocked functions....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/08/multiple-arguments-for-mocked-functions..../</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 21:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/08/multiple-arguments-for-mocked-functions..../</guid>
      <description>If you look into the PHPUnit documentation (http://www.phpunit.de/manual/3.3/en/test-doubles.html#test-doubles.mock-objects ) you&amp;rsquo;ll see some nice examples but non of them shows how to translate a function with multiple arguments into a mock-assumption.
Within the examples you&amp;rsquo;ll find: $observer-&amp;gt;expects($this-&amp;gt;once())-&amp;gt;method(&#39;update&#39;) -&amp;gt;with($this-&amp;gt;equalTo(&#39;something&#39;)); 
So what if the &amp;ldquo;update&amp;rdquo; function has two arguments, pretty easy: $observer-&amp;gt;expects($this-&amp;gt;once())-&amp;gt;method(&#39;update&#39;) -&amp;gt;with($this-&amp;gt;equalTo(&#39;something&#39;), $this-&amp;gt;equalTo(&#39;something else&#39;)); 
I guess Sebastian though that that there&amp;rsquo;s no need for documentation if something is so obvious :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>www.encodechain.com</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/08/www.encodechain.com/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 12:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/08/www.encodechain.com/</guid>
      <description>I just &amp;ldquo;released&amp;rdquo; encodechain.com. A little tool which enables to combine various popular PHP conversion methods and to check how they affect your input&amp;hellip; feel free to give me some feedback :)
I&amp;rsquo;m also not sure whether I choose the right name for it &amp;hellip; O_o</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser... hmmm</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/browser...-hmmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 21:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/browser...-hmmm/</guid>
      <description>The guys from Google tried to find out what a browser is :P
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4MwTvtyrUQ[/youtube]
(via)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 extensions ....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/typo3-extensions-..../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 19:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/typo3-extensions-..../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently within the preparation for some exams therefore my day&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t very fancy at all - and that&amp;rsquo;s why I just decided to introduce some TYPO3 extensions - especially TYPO3 extensions where I&amp;rsquo;m somehow involved ;)
The mentioned extensions are all created by AOEmedia or in cooperation with AOEmedia, they&amp;rsquo;re actively maintained and they work within regular TYPO3 environments with all TYPO3 features -lot&amp;rsquo;s of other extensions don&amp;rsquo;t support l10n and workspaces - ours do ;) Please use the mentioned pages on forge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 3.7 sneak....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/firefox-3.7-sneak..../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 21:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/firefox-3.7-sneak..../</guid>
      <description>I just stumbled over some Firefox 3.7 screens. It seems that the mozilla developers plan/brainstormed to change same smallers parts:
  Embracing Glass: Toolbar and Tabs using Glass. Buttons translucent and slightly glossy to meld with the toolbar. Raised 3D lookachieve tactile &amp;ldquo;feel&amp;rdquo;.
 Page Button: Connect the Page button to the left side of the tab area. Directly connected to the Page.
 Tools/Bookmark Bar: Connecting the Tools button to the side of the Window to emphasize the fact that it is used for customizing and changing the UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancy Wolfram Alpha queries .... </title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/fancy-wolfram-alpha-queries-..../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 21:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/fancy-wolfram-alpha-queries-..../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just got a tiny url from a friend ( click ) and this shows that Wolfram Alpha can also plot complex functions in a very nice way. All this is pretty amazing and I just found out that there are ton&amp;rsquo;s of examples how they process data ~ either by plotting mathematical things, calculation chemical stuff, doing string-analyses or plotting fractals :)
Btw - google looses on all of these queries :P (1) (2) (3) (4) (5)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Code Rush</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/project-code-rush/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2009 17:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/project-code-rush/</guid>
      <description>A pretty interesting documentation about the phase of the open source release of Mozilla in 1999. They just published this documentation (which aired 2000) because there&amp;rsquo;s no Copyright for it. I find it interesting because you can see why Open Source can succeed and you can also see why the Internet-Bubble was growing. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how these developers live and how they work. It&amp;rsquo;s scary that some of them found it normal to stay in their office for the entire week just to get rid of some bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>disable TemplaVoila new page wizard</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/disable-templavoila-new-page-wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 16:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/disable-templavoila-new-page-wizard/</guid>
      <description>TemplaVoila&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new page wizard&amp;rdquo; is a pretty cool featue - at least if your page templates have a thumbnail and a description. If your &amp;ldquo;new page wizard&amp;rdquo; look like the image on the right you might consider to turn it of.
That&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy just paste this into the Page TSConfig of your rootpage and you&amp;rsquo;re done: mod.web_list.newPageWiz.overrideWithExtension &amp;gt; Now you might wonder how TemplaVoila knows what template it should use to render the page - but due to the TV&amp;rsquo;s default behaviour to inherit the page-template this should not be a problem if there&amp;rsquo;s at least a TemplaVoila page template assigned for your root-page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 nerds community- share your location!</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-nerds-community--share-your-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 14:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-nerds-community--share-your-location/</guid>
      <description>Georg just published a nice littel mashup where you can place a pin on a Google-Map - It&amp;rsquo;s meant to show where the TYPO3 community is located and how big it is. It seems that already lot&amp;rsquo;s of people placed their pins - so what you&amp;rsquo;re waiting for? (click)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>optimize CSS and JS on the fly</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/optimize-css-and-js-on-the-fly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 23:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/optimize-css-and-js-on-the-fly/</guid>
      <description>Today I got the hint from a colleague that there&amp;rsquo;s some app from RockstarApps which enables to optimize CSS and JS in Eclipse on the fly. I just did some work on myimagemap_wizard TYPO3 extension and it seems to work pretty well - therefore I highly recommed to checkout the Rockstar WebOptimizer if you&amp;rsquo;re developing Javascript applications.
It seems that it also supports CSS sprite generation - this might be a followup tomorrow ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bash: small improvement for the &#34;cd&#34; builtin</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/bash-small-improvement-for-the-cd-builtin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2009 21:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/bash-small-improvement-for-the-cd-builtin/</guid>
      <description>If you use the shell and walk around in directories wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to have &amp;ldquo;cd &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; to move 2 levels up, &amp;ldquo;cd &amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo; to move 3 levels up &amp;hellip;? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s an easier way to resolve it but the following lines work pretty nice so far and they just made it into my default .bashrc :P
cd() { if [[ &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; =~ ^\.\.\.+$ ]]; then cd `echo &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; | sed &#39;s/\.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery performance</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/jquery-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 06:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/jquery-performance/</guid>
      <description>jQuery 1.3 made a huge step especially towards better performance. But it&amp;rsquo;s not only the framework, from time to time it&amp;rsquo;s the developer who should care about performance too. Artzstudio.com made up a really good summary of how you should change your coding-style to achieve a higher performance with jQuery.
In my opinion the most important things are:
 Use ID selectors whenever possible since this can be directly mapped to getElementById() it much faster then all the other selectors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my jQuery 1.3.2 update experience</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/my-jquery-1.3.2-update-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 07:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/my-jquery-1.3.2-update-experience/</guid>
      <description>Over the last days I did some small steps to clean up the code of my TYPO3 imagemap extension. During that process I wanted to update jQuery from 1.2.6 to 1.3.2. Initially this went fine but after some testing I found this strange error:
[Exception... &amp;quot;&#39;Syntax error, unrecognized expression: #&#39; when calling method: [nsIDOMEventListener::handleEvent]&amp;quot; nsresult: &amp;quot;0x8057001e (NS_ERROR_XPC_JS_THREW_STRING)&amp;quot; location: &amp;quot;&amp;lt;unknown&amp;gt;&amp;quot;
Due to the verbosity of the message (location &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; ) it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious for me that what&amp;rsquo;s going wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>last week....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/last-week..../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2009 17:42:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/last-week..../</guid>
      <description>This week has gone by so very fast - the most interesting thing was that Tetris is now 25 years old. Happy birthday :)
After 2.5 years of work the TYPO3 guys published the first Alpha version of FLOW3 - that&amp;rsquo;s the amazing framework for TYPO3 Version 5 and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to test it. Since they decided to have a &amp;ldquo;release&amp;rdquo; every month the next alpha will be ready at the beginning of July.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolfram Alpha ... knows the answer :P</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/wolfram-alpha-...-knows-the-answer-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2009 20:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/wolfram-alpha-...-knows-the-answer-p/</guid>
      <description>The answer to life, the universe and everything &amp;lt;&amp;lt; that was easy but what about famous people like Homer Simpson? D&amp;rsquo;oh! OK last try - any results for &amp;lsquo;tolleiv&amp;rsquo; .. no? thanks :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 extensions from Subversion</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-extensions-from-subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 11:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-extensions-from-subversion/</guid>
      <description>[(/uploads/2009/06/svn2t3x-snap.png)
From time to time it&amp;rsquo;s really buggin me that some &amp;ldquo;TYPO3 integrators&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t have PHP skills. And since Subversion is imho the most important tool within groups of developers, their missing PHP skills are a real downside because they can&amp;rsquo;t use the newest extension version directly out of the Subversion repository. Therefore I decided to create a handy little tool which enables to generate TYPO3 .t3x extension-files from any Subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP Best practice comparison</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/php-best-practice-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 10:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/php-best-practice-comparison/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re still wondering whether the single- or double quotes are processed faster in PHP you might want to look at phpbench.com. They don&amp;rsquo;t provide any ground breaking new insights, but they show in a very nice way what&amp;rsquo;s best pratice when it comes to arrays, strings and loops&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>some free music</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/some-free-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 13:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/some-free-music/</guid>
      <description>This week my iPod also got some fresh music. Coldplay published their Live-Album LeftRightLeftRightLeft (via), some blogs published Daft Punk remixes (via), Mike Skinner from The Strees pushed some music via Twitter into the web &amp;ldquo;The Twitter&amp;rdquo; (via) and just a few minutes ago the Sub Pop CyberSex Sampler found the way into my iPod (via). Pretty good week so far :P
Finally a Beethoven-remix from Soulwax (via) [audio:http://cache03-music02.myspacecdn.com/61/std_9b57d13da38e4c6b80e3e8dddf7580a8.mp3]
Edit: Music To Feed Your Soul During Crucial Design Moments</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop-Timetracking</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/desktop-timetracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 09:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/desktop-timetracking/</guid>
      <description>I just saw that Heiner already published a new (stable) version of his Desktop-Timetracking software. Within this version he did a lot of refactoring - actually I helped out with some work and with lot&amp;rsquo;s of smart³ comments ;) - and I&amp;rsquo;m really proud that I got him into TDD. Check out DPDesktop at sourceforge.net</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morrissey</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/morrissey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 19:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/morrissey/</guid>
      <description>Wow happy belated b-day old man ;)
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ke1-MTDBAro[/youtube]
via</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 templavoila rtfm</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/typo3-templavoila-rtfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 21:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/typo3-templavoila-rtfm/</guid>
      <description>Dmitry and Steffen included some of the AOE guys (including me) into the TemplaVoila team and we all try to contribute into the project from now on. Therefore I just checked the Unit-tests for TemplaVoila and tried to find a way how to improve them in the future and somewhere within the tx_templavoila_api -Class I found the PageTS key &amp;ldquo;tx_templavoila.storagePid&amp;rdquo;. That seems to be some kind of nice workaround for everyone who&amp;rsquo;s not interested to mess up the TYPO3 general record storage page with the TemplaVoila DS/TO storage-folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streetart ...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/streetart-.../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 20:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/streetart-.../</guid>
      <description>Smashing Mag. just brought out a great collection of graffiti artworks. Seems that they forgot some of the great stuff from spain ~ Flickr #1, Flickr#2, Flickr #3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eintracht Frankfurt last Saturday</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/eintracht-frankfurt-last-saturday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 20:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/eintracht-frankfurt-last-saturday/</guid>
      <description>I just found this on YouTube &amp;hellip; I was in the stadium and that was the saddest moment on Saturday - spending 34€ to see such a lousy game with two stupid goals for the opponents.
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I8FpvwMTMKI[/youtube]
I can&amp;rsquo;t really imagine how they got their 32 points during the season and I don&amp;rsquo;t really like the way the played soccer over the last few years - during the second half they didn&amp;rsquo;t even really shout into the direction of Dortmunds goal :( - currently I think that it can&amp;rsquo;t get worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hilarious commercial</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/hilarious-commercial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 20:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/hilarious-commercial/</guid>
      <description>[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MUJ4uorYPoY[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eläkeläiset in Wiesbaden</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/el%C3%A4kel%C3%A4iset-in-wiesbaden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 17:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/el%C3%A4kel%C3%A4iset-in-wiesbaden/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t pronounce their name but the party was great &amp;hellip; Eläkeläiset from Finnland (WP Eläkeläiset)
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=43LenTNSHY8[/youtube]
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B4eX1F8EvmM[/youtube]
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1JHxWxF-lKA[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Sprites ... a nice way to save bandwidth</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/css-sprites-...-a-nice-way-to-save-bandwidth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 20:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/css-sprites-...-a-nice-way-to-save-bandwidth/</guid>
      <description>I saw some of these sprites long time ago on some spiegel.de subpage and from time to time I see smaller sprites within stuff I get from our HTML-team - but this article and it&amp;rsquo;s insights into realworld design, is really great &amp;hellip; continue on Smashing Mag - The Mystery Of CSS Sprites
And that&amp;rsquo;s where you should start with it - as always AListApart is the best source for Web-Designers &amp;hellip; AListApart about Sprites</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shell command: translate </title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/shell-command-translate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2009 16:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/shell-command-translate/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Translate, squeeze, and/or delete characters from standard input, writing to standard output.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s the manpage description of the shell-command I just found (with the help of a good friend) &amp;hellip; and besides sed this is a very handy way to do simple string-operations on stdin.
He used it to replace (old) Mac newline characters with Unix newline charaters within files (as seen on wikipedia): tr &#39;\r&#39; &#39;\n&#39; &amp;lt; old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>around the world</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/around-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2009 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/around-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Seems that this year I might have the chance to travel a lot and I also planned to go to London. I hope that besides my business-trips I find some time to go to london this summer. I hope that video keeps my motivation a but higher: [vimeo]http://vimeo.com/2169237[/vimeo]
Btw. I learned to play Daft Punk&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Around the world on a guitar 11 years ago. It is actually the only thing I every learned on a guitar &amp;mdash; maybe someone could borrow me a guitar for some days so that I can pratice again :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death Star Over San Francisco</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/death-star-over-san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 23:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/death-star-over-san-francisco/</guid>
      <description>Mike Horn saw the Death Star Over San Francisco and he was able to spread it around the internet before the new emperor punished him for this nice artwork :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History and cookbooks are written by the victors...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/history-and-cookbooks-are-written-by-the-victors.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2009 09:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/history-and-cookbooks-are-written-by-the-victors.../</guid>
      <description>Just found a good starter for today :P &amp;hellip; old american Lady is complaining about raw salmon &amp;hellip;on notalwaysright.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the subshell is your friend</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/the-subshell-is-your-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 21:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/the-subshell-is-your-friend/</guid>
      <description>Today I tried to find a way to track the time of a shell-command and to log that runtime into a file. I was already aware of the **time **command which is a bash build-in. Due to that it passes its output directly to the user without using either stdout or stderr and therefore there&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; way to redirect the output directly into a file.
But bash als provides subshells and in this case that&amp;rsquo;s how you can use the output :P (which is passed on stderr in this case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/visualization..../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 19:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/visualization..../</guid>
      <description>Wow check this out - Spreeblick one of Germanys most popular blogs had some kind of protest agains the governments internet filter some days ago. They asked their users to click on a germany-map and leave a comment to &amp;ldquo;vote&amp;rdquo; against the filter.
Afterwards they published the XML-Data of this and Micheal Schieben published this very impressive visualization of the internet-protest . It was produced with processing (one of my early loves) and he also published the source-code &amp;hellip; great work :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>webdesign and stuff that came along my way today</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine recommended this URL in regards to one topic which I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on: Designing Drop-Down Menus: Examples and Best Practices . This article about how to use Drop-Down menus within the navigation, including some DOs and some DONTs, is a very nice summary for anyone who creates designs with these elements.
After I scanned that article, I found another one which will be my default answer in the future whenever clients or coworkers ask strange questions about features and designs: 9 Common Usability Mistakes In Web Design | How-To | Smashing Magazine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>moments</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 18:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/moments/</guid>
      <description>I just stumpled over this video while the piano in the room next to me played some strange ronan keating song&amp;hellip; what a moment :D
[vimeo]http://vimeo.com/2585249?pg=embed&amp;amp;sec=2585249[/vimeo]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualized sorting algorithms</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/visualized-sorting-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 20:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/visualized-sorting-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>There are lot&amp;rsquo;s of visualizations for soting algorithms - this pages provides all relevant informations including runtime complexity and extra space requirements etc - and a easy to memorize domain name ;) ~ http://www.sorting-algorithms.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>... much better way to use your shell</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/...-much-better-way-to-use-your-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 19:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/...-much-better-way-to-use-your-shell/</guid>
      <description>[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x7pPajOvQGo[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>find the newest file within a folder....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/find-the-newest-file-within-a-folder..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2009 20:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/find-the-newest-file-within-a-folder..../</guid>
      <description>These are two neat little commands to find the newest and oldest file within a folder and it&amp;rsquo;s subfolder: find . -type f -printf &amp;quot;%T@ %p \n&amp;quot; | sort -n -k 1,1 | awk &#39;{print $2}&#39; | tail -n 1 find . -type f -printf &amp;quot;%T@ %p \n&amp;quot; | sort -n -k 1,1 | awk &#39;{print $2}&#39; | head -n 1 If you&amp;rsquo;d like to know how old/young these files are try these two: find .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bye bye version 4...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/08/bye-bye-version-4.../</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/08/bye-bye-version-4.../</guid>
      <description>Ten years ago Andi Gutmans and Zeev Suraski started to renew the old PHP3 core and in 1999 PHP4 was published and became really famous among Web-Developers.
Bute 5 years late the successor was published and since then everyone is wondering why the era of PHP4 will end.
Today is the magical 8-8-8 where PHP4 is no longer supported so for everyone who still runs PHP4 for some reason
YOU SHOW NOW REALLY HAVE A LOOK AT THIS PAGE: www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B-Tree simulation...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/b-tree-simulation.../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 19:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/b-tree-simulation.../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m just preparing for some of my computer science exams and in one of my researches I found a really great B-Tree simulation and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share it: http://slady.net/java/bt/view.php &amp;hellip;..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working from home.</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/working-from-home./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 17:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/working-from-home./</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s so much work in this week that I can&amp;rsquo;t publish a article in the next days.
But Natalie Jost from A List Apart just published a very nice article which you really should read if you&amp;rsquo;re (like me) working from home read on.. &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>musique ... britisch musique :P</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/musique-...-britisch-musique-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/musique-...-britisch-musique-p/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>track time for a subroutine within a shell-script</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/track-time-for-a-subroutine-within-a-shell-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2008 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/track-time-for-a-subroutine-within-a-shell-script/</guid>
      <description>The following code-snippet is a shell-script which does the following:
 Track the time for a block of shell commands
 Check if the time was less than x seconds (the example uses 10 seconds)
 If the block run through too fast the script waits/sleeps a few seconds
 Run all this within a loop so that the block of shell-commands is executed periodically
  I used the script combined with a PHP script which processes a queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterator [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/iterator-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/iterator-gof/</guid>
      <description>Lot&amp;rsquo;s of people like to write down things into lists, so that they can go through that list later and check whether everything was fine. Normally every recipe has a list ~ there&amp;rsquo;s always a list of ingredients at the beginning of the recipe. This short example shows how such a list can be processed in PHP. So why would you want to have something else than a array to hold your objects?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how breakfast could look like...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/how-breakfast-could-look-like.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/how-breakfast-could-look-like.../</guid>
      <description>hey that&amp;rsquo;s great - my mom never created something like this for me:
check out on: http://fiveprime.org/hivemind/Tags/bento</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>our wonderful nature</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/our-wonderful-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2008 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/our-wonderful-nature/</guid>
      <description>Nice video I just found on some german page:
Our wonderful nature by Tomer Eshed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null-Object Pattern</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/null-object-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/null-object-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Very often you create a object with a factory and before you really start using it, you check if your factory really created a object or returned NULL. Or maybe you have a method where a object is passed in and in this situation you&amp;rsquo;ll have to do this check also.
Instead of typing the &amp;ldquo;if(object == null)&amp;rdquo; phrase again and again, you could use the Null-Object pattern, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that this can make some situations much clearer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chronotopic anamorphosis</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/chronotopic-anamorphosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 09:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/07/chronotopic-anamorphosis/</guid>
      <description>The start is a bit lame but the end is just mind-blowing:
Chronotopic Anamorphosis from Marginalia Project on Vimeo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YSlow - powerful FF extension</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/yslow---powerful-ff-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/yslow---powerful-ff-extension/</guid>
      <description>I use firebug for a while and I love it especially for CSS and JS debugging. Today I stumbled over Yslow and did some tests with it one some of my clients pages and I love the results.
YSlow can help you to analyze all the referenced elements on a webpage. It shows their sizes, how they behave when a page is taken from the browser-cache, shows optimization hints and enables a easy way to optimize the output of your dynamically created webpage :) &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ll love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>musique</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/musique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/musique/</guid>
      <description>sooo nice :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factory [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/factory-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/factory-gof/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember the Façade pattern post? Sure you do :) - I described a child which asked his granny whether she could bake some cookies. So how this happens in a formal way was describe within theFaçade pattern post ;) but the basic action &amp;ldquo;to ask for sth.&amp;rdquo; is described here&amp;hellip;
As you might remember we had a child, probably a lazy one, which was in the mood to eat some cookies but since the cookie tin was empty it asked his granny to bake some new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Query Object [PoEEA]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/query-object-poeea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2008 17:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/query-object-poeea/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you remember the Specification Pattern I explained some weeks ago. It enabled a easy and intuitive searching within large object-collections. A drawback of my example was that I stored the objects in the memory. This can be really ineffective if you want a single object out of hundreds, because you have to create all of them to see which one fits the specification. Normally you want to limit the number of objects and you also don&amp;rsquo;t store large datasets in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>... I laughed</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/...-i-laughed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/...-i-laughed/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine just posted that to the IM:
&amp;ldquo;Hey they finally found water on the mars&amp;hellip; this pic proves it: http://apod.nasa.gov/apod/image/0504/WaterOnMars2_gcc.jpg&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;. kkthxbye</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Façade [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/fa%C3%A7ade-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 23:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/fa%C3%A7ade-gof/</guid>
      <description>If a child is in the mood to eat a fresh cookie it normally asks his granny for one. Like this:
Child: Grannyyyyy?
Granny: Yes my dear?
Child: Could you mix about 2 cups of sugar, 1&amp;frasl;2 cup of butter and 1&amp;frasl;2 cup of milk in a saucepan and boil it for a minute. And could you, after you removed the saucepan from the heat, mix in some cocoa powder and 3 cups quick cooking oats and form some cookies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s Rofl</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/todays-rofl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 22:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/todays-rofl/</guid>
      <description>I just found this with the Stumble-Button: http://www.lessaid.net/fun/apt-get-wife.png - so true :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inherit abstract functions....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/inherit-abstract-functions..../</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/inherit-abstract-functions..../</guid>
      <description>A error I find from time to time when I work with inheritance is this one:
Fatal error: Can&amp;rsquo;t inherit abstract function Cookie::setFlavor() (previously declared abstract in ChocolateCookie) in &amp;hellip;
This happens when you try to define multiple abstract classes or interfaces with the same abstract functions - it&amp;rsquo;s right that this errors shows up, but today I stuck on this error for a while because I did not see the reason for that - so that&amp;rsquo;s a reminder for me ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new TYPO releases</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/new-typo-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/new-typo-releases/</guid>
      <description>I just saw that the TYPO3 guys released a new version of the popular Enterprise CMS (www.typo3.org). The changelog shows that they mainly changed some security issues and that a lot of smaller changes in the backend happend - one change relates to the problems in the new Firefox 3 where all the frames in the backend are mixed up for some compatibility reason&amp;hellip; this was also the reason why the also updates the 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-extracting PHP archive</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/self-extracting-php-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2008 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/self-extracting-php-archive/</guid>
      <description>The __halt_compiler(); function in php enables to store some additional data in a php-file without blowing up the memory. A very nice possibility is to use this for a self-extracting php file as installation-packages of your php application. A wile ago I created a script which automatically creates such a archive and I think you might like it&amp;hellip;.for the impatient ones: Download / Download as Zip.
Before I start to show how the entire script works I&amp;rsquo;d like to show you a small example so that you can see how the __halt_compiler(); function can be used to store some data at the end of a file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dunno why but I love this song...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/dunno-why-but-i-love-this-song.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2008 15:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/dunno-why-but-i-love-this-song.../</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin [PoEAA]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/plugin-poeaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 01:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/plugin-poeaa/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;re pretty often in the situation that you have to switch something depending on the context you&amp;rsquo;re currently in. For example most people change their eating habits before summer - I also do :P
Sometimes this is what you also want to have in your software. To achieve different behaviour you normally just implement two different classes or aggregates and since they have the same &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; they normally share a interface (a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing PHP Best Practises</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/comparing-php-best-practises/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 15:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/06/comparing-php-best-practises/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re still wondering whether the single- or double quotes are processed faster in PHP you might want to look at phpbench.com. They don&amp;rsquo;t provide any ground breaking new insights, but they show in a very nice way what&amp;rsquo;s best pratice when it comes to arrays, strings and loops&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value Object [DDD]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/value-object-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 04:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/value-object-ddd/</guid>
      <description>This metaphor does not fit completely, and the &amp;ldquo;Money-Example&amp;rdquo; is omnipresent, but I really like the pattern and so that&amp;rsquo;s the story:
Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have your grannies recipe for a chocolate cookie and you want to keep this in mind, but also you like to somehow experiment with some new or different ingredients. Normally you just keep in mind what you changed and later you write down the new recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today&#39;s Rofl</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/todays-rofl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/todays-rofl/</guid>
      <description>These two storries passed my day and I really like them Oo
Calls for free and how this can get back to you&amp;hellip; and I hope that I never meet the officer in this story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototype [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/prototype-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/prototype-gof/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a cookie-oven which produces tasty cookies with chocolate crumbles. How do you ensure that the 1000th cookie still has the same taste as the first? You might think that this is an easy task - just write down the recipe and follow the described steps&amp;hellip;you know the result in real life - the 1000th cookie normally tasts like the 1st but you always had the &amp;ldquo;overhead&amp;rdquo; to read the recipe and go through the steps again and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wii Head-tracking</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/wii-head-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/wii-head-tracking/</guid>
      <description>The page and the experiments with the Wii-Remote controll are really great: http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/
And for the spare time a cool video - I watch it every monday morning to get into the new week with a smile:
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/?v=HIicO-e0hic[/youtube]
The second one is also cool:
[youtube]http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6VKE_VoXzNI[/youtube]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP FastCGI vs. PHP as a module</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-fastcgi-vs.-php-as-a-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-fastcgi-vs.-php-as-a-module/</guid>
      <description>The apachelounge.org guy published a very interesting stat which compares the memory-usage of PHP/FastCGI and PHP/as module and that&amp;rsquo;s really interesting:

There&amp;rsquo;s no comment about performance and in early versions FastCGI/PHP was a bottleneck but maybe these days are gone :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Singelton [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/singelton-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2008 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/singelton-gof/</guid>
      <description>Tis pattern is a very well know and a often discussed one.
Explaining it the tasty way: let&amp;rsquo;s say you have exactly one well know place where you store all your cookies and whenever you need one you can easy point to that place. Normally that&amp;rsquo;s really comfortable because whatever you do with it, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to search some place where you can find a cookie, you just go to that single &amp;ldquo;cookie tin&amp;rdquo; (or wherever you store cookies) and put a new cookie into it ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PHP sucks? not really!</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-sucks-not-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 06:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/php-sucks-not-really/</guid>
      <description>There are so many people from outside of the PHP World and lots of them are complaining about PHP and their reasons are mostly so ridiculous. In most cases they just say that PHP code sucks.
The PHP 10.0 Blog brought up some good arguments about that and I fully agree - it&amp;rsquo;s not the language that produces sucking code, it&amp;rsquo;s the guy who wrote it down. Click</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>error_reposting and exceptions....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/error_reposting-and-exceptions..../</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 21:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/error_reposting-and-exceptions..../</guid>
      <description>I just found this line:
set_error_handler(create_function(&amp;lsquo;$x, $y&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;throw new Exception($y, $x);&amp;rsquo;), E_ALL~E_NOTICE);
in the comments on php.net and did a short test to see whether it works. Normally I used to have a global function which passes all the errors through a logging-chain (FILE/MAIL/DISPLAY) but having exceptions could be more comfortable because you might sometimes want to make decisions locally and not on a global scope and just setting and re-setting the error-handler is not the best idea for this&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I get used to it, because the error-handling function did a good job for the last years &amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ll see :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preview to PHP 5.3</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/preview-to-php-5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 05:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/preview-to-php-5.3/</guid>
      <description>One of the mayor updates since PHP 5.0 is upcoming with the 5.3 version, this is also a major step forward to PHP 6 - I love to have namespaces and appreciate the split of E_NOTICE and E_DEPRECATED. Also other features like the native MySQL support ( I hope this really raises the performance), the array_replace/array_replace_recursive functions and also dynamic calls to static functions &amp;ldquo;$classname::$functionname($parameter);&amp;rdquo; sound very cool. So I really look forward to have it on the server (or at least on my laptop) :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox 3 RC1</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/firefox-3-rc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/firefox-3-rc1/</guid>
      <description>I just saw that the first Release Candidate of Firefox 3 is available for download . As with the most of the Beta-versions I also checked this update because I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to get the new features, but after 5 minutes (again) I removed it from my PC. Non of my extensions is working in FF3 (except the dictionary), it still destroys the Frames in TYPO3 (there&amp;rsquo;s a bugfix-extension for that) and the memory-usage is still very high,10% lower than in FF2 but still high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Mocks within Tests</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/using-mocks-within-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/using-mocks-within-tests/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you have some kind of process which creates cookies and which requires the cookies to bake before you deliver them to the customers. This process somehow touches two kinds of objects the cookie itself and a object which performs the process - the cookie oven. When you start to develop the oven how do you check whether the cookies are really baked or not? Since you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of the dependency between the oven and the cookie, you have to simulate a real object and do the checks by hand - but wait there&amp;rsquo;s already a way to resolve it: PHPUnit ships with a very nice and comfortable function to create and check mock-objects and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we need in this situation where we somehow need to find out if our cookie really gets baked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 API...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/typo3-api.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/typo3-api.../</guid>
      <description>The API documentation on typo3.org is not very up-to-date, but the typo3-unleashed.net guys just provided some links to the API documentation of the current TYPO3 versions - http://www.typo3-unleashed.net/api_online.html - thanks a lot :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specification [DDD]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/specification-ddd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/specification-ddd/</guid>
      <description>Maybe sometimes the cookie tin is filled with all sorts of cookies and only some of them are what you&amp;rsquo;d like in this special moment. Often it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to specify which cookie you like, but sometimes your wishes are very complex, for example if you look for grannies special cookie with chocolate, coconut and vanilla crumbles. This could lead into a real crumby problem if you try to sort all the cookies and then select eat the right one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homer Simpson as ASCII-Art</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/homer-simpson-as-ascii-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2008 22:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/homer-simpson-as-ascii-art/</guid>
      <description>The rebirth of ASCII-Art that&amp;rsquo;s how one of the comments called it - Homer-Simpson as ASCII-Art with modern and valid CSS - that&amp;rsquo;s so awesome: http://www.romancortes.com/blog/homer-css/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3DD08</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/t3dd08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/t3dd08/</guid>
      <description>The last weekend was great, I joined the T3DD in Elmshorn, Germany and meet a lot of interesting people, the beer was cheap and the weather was amazing. So I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the T3CON in autumn&amp;hellip; :)
It also seems that some of the guys got some new spirit - today 4 official and some inofficial bugs in some extensions had been fixed in a very short sequence &amp;hellip; great!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memento [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/memento-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2008 07:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/memento-gof/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you got a cookie from a repository your granny and you&amp;rsquo;re not sure if you like the new taste. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool if you could just try it and revoke the operation first bite if you don&amp;rsquo;t like it?
In the world of OOP thats a easy job which can be handled by the so called memento pattern - you just save the inner state of the object within a memento object and revoke you actions whenever you like&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decorator [GoF]</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/decorator-gof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/decorator-gof/</guid>
      <description>As the first pattern I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce the decorator pattern - it&amp;rsquo;s one of the [GoF]- structural patterns. It enables to extend the functionality of a existing method by wrapping a so called decorator-object.
So maybe you already know the situation ;) , your granny is going to bake cookies and you think of how they gonna taste - so cookie is our main-object and the different additional spices and other options which refine the taste of the cookies are the decoration for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3CON07</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2007/09/t3con07/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2007 23:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2007/09/t3con07/</guid>
      <description>Visiting the T3CON07 was one of the best choices I made in the last weeks. After years of being in touch with some people on newslists and working with this great CMS its so great to finally meat some of them. I found lots of new inspiration and motivation for the upcoming tasks and found some new perspectives as well. New topics like the content repository, TYPO3 version 5 and large scale localization also found my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>