<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Typo3 on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </title>
    <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/tags/typo3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typo3 on blog.tolleiv.de ...  </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tolleiv&#34;&gt;tolleiv&lt;/a&gt; 2016 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt; - Powered by Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 15:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//blog.tolleiv.de/tags/typo3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 login state and Varnish cache</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/typo3-login-state-and-varnish-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 15:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/12/typo3-login-state-and-varnish-cache/</guid>
      <description>Caching is hard in complex page setups with user specific content, especially when public pages change their content once a user is logged in. TYPO3 is smart enough to deal with the login state properly and cache appropriately. Once Varnish is involved, it&amp;rsquo;s quite tricky to cache as much as possible without loosing the dynamic content. But it&amp;rsquo;s not impossible and here&amp;rsquo;s my summary how we resolved it for typo3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding TypoScript errors.</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/02/finding-typoscript-errors./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 16:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/02/finding-typoscript-errors./</guid>
      <description>When you work on TypoScript templates in TYPO3, errors might show up in the TypoScript Object Browser. Within the error messages you&amp;rsquo;ll see a more or less detailed error description with the related line number. Within most setups these line numbers won&amp;rsquo;t relate to any of your sys_template records or TypoScript files directly. But they still provide value if you know how they help to find the right spot. As it&amp;rsquo;s not too obvious how to find the right spot I&amp;rsquo;ve created a little screenshot series to guide you to the broken spots in your templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing TYPO3 Core activity</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/visualizing-typo3-core-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 08:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/visualizing-typo3-core-activity/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: Don&amp;rsquo;t take the following too serious - when reading this post please keep in mind that the TYPO3 community itself consists of much more than just the Core team activity - many things take place outside of code repositories and can&amp;rsquo;t be measured anyhow. Every contribution is important and every single action has value.
 Using Gerrit sometimes feels quite lonesome - you don&amp;rsquo;t really see who&amp;rsquo;s active and you don&amp;rsquo;t really get a feeling on how much is done in the TYPO3 Core at a certain point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.6.x</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/templavoila-1.6.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 07:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2012/01/templavoila-1.6.x/</guid>
      <description>Quite some things changed in the past months and I never found the time to clear up my mind and write up a summary.
First of all TemplaVoila 1.6 was released parallel to TYPO3 4.6. It shipped with 22 bug and compatibility fixes. In general the 1.6.x branch is supposed to be compatible with TYPO3 4.4+ which also made it possible to clean up the extension quite a bit. In addition to that TemplaVoila 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging page caches</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/tagging-page-caches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 17:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/12/tagging-page-caches/</guid>
      <description>In our small TYPO3 world it&amp;rsquo;s quite common to have list and single views for extensions on specific pages. That&amp;rsquo;s quite nice because once a record is changed it allowes users to flush the caches for these pages automatically, using:
TCEMAIN.clearCacheCmd=all|&amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;  But of course it isn&amp;rsquo;t very smart to clear all caches once you have filled them up for hundred or even thousand records. To work around these limits it&amp;rsquo;s quite handy to use an API which lives in TYPO3 since 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal / Slots in Extbase</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/11/signal-/-slots-in-extbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 17:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/11/signal-/-slots-in-extbase/</guid>
      <description>A nice thing to have at hand is definately Signal and Slots. I heard Felix talking about them quite often and I finally found a nice usecase and came to play with them a little bit this afternoon. And just to avoid that others have to look around too much to find how they can get them to work here&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s working for me.
First of all you should understand the concept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release reviews (templavoila, imagemap_wizard, workspaces)</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/02/release-reviews-templavoila-imagemap_wizard-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 21:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2011/02/release-reviews-templavoila-imagemap_wizard-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>I just push the TER upload button two times and in addition to that TYPO3 4.5.2 will be released tomorrow containing some nice workspaces updates. So here&amp;rsquo;s a short summary what happened in the extension releases.
TemplaVoila 1.5.4 The current release focussed on 4.5 compatibility. It uses the new sys_language flag &amp;ldquo;format&amp;rdquo; to support sprites, it hooks into the new backend-form (TCA) &amp;ldquo;layout&amp;rdquo; and add&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s fields to the right tabs within the backend forms and adjusts everything to work fine with the new CSRF mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.5 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/10/templavoila-1.5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 20:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/10/templavoila-1.5-released/</guid>
      <description>The new version comes with many bugfixes,new features and a closer TYPO3 integration. Overall 95 issues have been resolved in the last 4 months to finalize this versions, some of the highlights are:
HTML5 support The full list of HTML5 tags is now supported in TemplaVoila. The restrictions to specific tags was removed and the TYPO3 integrator is now able to use the full bandwidth of modern HTML. With this change also the tag-icons themself were replaced and the coloring schema was changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 4.4 sprites in your extension...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/typo3-4.4-sprites-in-your-extension.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 08:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/typo3-4.4-sprites-in-your-extension.../</guid>
      <description>TYPO3 4.4 ships with a long list of improvements. One of them is the sprite API which was developed during T3UXW09. It extends the iconWorks API and enables to retrieve any backend-icon from a central sprite.
As extension maintainer there are several ways to use these new parts of the API you can either just use it to display core icons, you can include your own icons and retrieve it with the new API or you can include your own sprite and retrieve the separate icons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>T3DD10 Git workshop</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/t3dd10-git-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 22:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/07/t3dd10-git-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I just found that Peter shares the slides of the Git workshop from the T3DD10 on slideshare. Since this 4 hour workshop was - for many reasons - one of my favorites during the T3DD10, I felt that it&amp;rsquo;s worth to mention it. And due to the fact that TYPO3 is moving very fast towards Git it&amp;rsquo;s worth to look at them ;) &amp;mdash; Open workshop slides
Btw. at the beginning I didn&amp;rsquo;t belief that a Git workshop could fill 4 hours - now I don&amp;rsquo;t think that shorter workshops make any sense :P</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using git svn for TYPO3 extension development</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/using-git-svn-for-typo3-extension-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 06:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/using-git-svn-for-typo3-extension-development/</guid>
      <description>When I first saw a presentation about Git 2 years ago I liked it, but I was convinced that Subversion covers all I need. Things have changed and especially the bad performance of Subversion for larger repositories and the need to commit things without messing up the official trunk motivated me to look up how to get started with Git. If you need more reasons why you should look into Git, you&amp;rsquo;ll find them in [7] - anyways it&amp;rsquo;s worth to have a look how I managed to work with it ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 workspaces</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/typo3-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 17:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/06/typo3-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>One of the enterprise features TYPO3 has to offer is versioning and workspace handling. Kasper did a great job when he initially brough these featues into TYPO3. Unfortunately during the last years they became orphans and nobody really took care of them. There are multiple reasons for that, one was that Kasper didn&amp;rsquo;t allow big changes, another one was that everyone was somehow able to live with the existing odds they had but probable the most important one was that it was just to complicated to improve them alone without knowing the big picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tiny update...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/05/tiny-update.../</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2010 16:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/05/tiny-update.../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty busy in these days and unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s not much time to write blogposts. In detail there&amp;rsquo;s currently a long list of feature wishes and bugs for TemplaVoila which need my attention and in addition I also already started to prepare a workshop for the T3DD10 about Git*.
Just to keep this blog alive this is what I found interesting during the last weeks:
For TYPO3 enthusiasts especially the changes within the TYPO3 Core regarding the integration of further T3UX09 results and all the small changes which happen to get 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crawler 3.1 release &#43; podcast</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/crawler-3.1-release---podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2010 22:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/crawler-3.1-release---podcast/</guid>
      <description>Nearly a month after version 3.0.5, we published 3.1.0 of the well known crawler extension today. The main work for that step was related to several bugfixes, a better scheduler integration, some CLI-API enhancements, better testcases and (finally) some documentation updates. Most kudos go to Michael Klapper who took over the responsibility for this release and who also fixed a decent amount of bugs. You can download the extension in the TER  and hopefully this time OpenOffice didn&amp;rsquo;t trick us again and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see a shiny new extension manual on typo3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.4.2 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/templavoila-1.4.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2010 23:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/templavoila-1.4.2-released/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday the 2nd team release of TemplaVoila was uploaded into the TER. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a maintenance release which fixes more than 100 bugs. But since we haven&amp;rsquo;t been that straight distinguishing between bug and usability feature, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a couple of new things within this release.
The high level release notes are:
 page module is now customizable with CSS and JavaScript
 handling of static data structures are improved and fully working now</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Farewell, TemplaVoila!</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/re-farewell-templavoila/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 23:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/re-farewell-templavoila/</guid>
      <description>Dmitry decided to leave the TemplaVoilà project today and he handed the extension-leadership to me. Since this is a very abrupt change and since there was lot&amp;rsquo;s of (mis)communication involved I&amp;rsquo;d like to use this blogpost to answer his &amp;ldquo;Farewell, TemplaVoila!&amp;rdquo; post (he turned off the commenting function).
As you might know Steffen Kamper and I joined the TemplaVoilà team some time ago and since Dmitry wasn&amp;rsquo;t very motivated to maintain the extension anymore, we took over and tried to make TemplaVoilà ready for TYPO3 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling data in TYPO3 with tcemain</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/handling-data-in-typo3-with-tcemain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 07:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/03/handling-data-in-typo3-with-tcemain/</guid>
      <description>TYPO3 is (by definition) a powerful tool when it comes to data. Besides creating, updating and deleting data there are also localizing and versioning, logging and even rollbacks. All this is provided through the GUI of TYPO3 and all the technical stuff in working under the hood of TYPO3 for nearly every piece of data. But what if you&amp;rsquo;re asked to write a script which imports or updates data, how can you make sure that all this is done in a TYPO3 compatible way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>crawler extension version 3.0.5 released</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/02/crawler-extension-version-3.0.5-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 15:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2010/02/crawler-extension-version-3.0.5-released/</guid>
      <description>Quite some time after the 4.3 release of TYPO3, we published the necessary compatibility version of the crawler extension. Besides the compatibility fixes for TYPO3 and also for PHP 5.3 we also included some handy features:
First of all there&amp;rsquo;s now, besides the CLI interface, also a full integration with the scheduler extension, which is available in TYPO3 4.3. This enables to setup crawler runs and manage all crawler releated tasks through the TYPO3 backend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 4.3 release</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/typo3-4.3-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 18:05:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/typo3-4.3-release/</guid>
      <description>Today the TYPO3 Core Team released version 4.3 (release-notes on typo3.org).
Finally the list of improvements is long and the amount of cool new features is outstanding compared to other releases. Imho especially the security and performance-improvements are remarkable as well as the improved usability in the backend. But I guess my favorite improvement is obvious (hint hint) :P
In addition to TYPO3 4.3 a new major version of the tt_news (ter) extension was released over the weekend (Rupert Germans announcement on lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TemplaVoila 1.4 released...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/templavoila-1.4-released.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 20:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/11/templavoila-1.4-released.../</guid>
      <description>A new version of TemplaVoila (ter) (forge) has just been released. Besides the great fact that this is the first team-release of TemplaVoila, the high-level improvements within the pagemodule (drag&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;drop), the mapping module and the FCE editing forms and besides lot&amp;rsquo;s of bug fixes, there are a few very nice features which make the day-to-day work with TemplaVoila much easier.
The list of things which happend in 1.4 can be seen on bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 Core Changelog feeded</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/typo3-core-changelog-feeded/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 20:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/typo3-core-changelog-feeded/</guid>
      <description>It seems that the newsgroup is a nice tool for the discussion but not to keep track of the actual changes -To get an idea of what actually happend at the code-base usually you might want to look at the ChangeLog. Therefore I had a script which converted the ChangeLog to an atom feed - a couple of colleagues liked this idea and asked me to publish it - so here it is: http://feeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>imagemap_wizard 0.5.3</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/imagemap_wizard-0.5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 19:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/10/imagemap_wizard-0.5.3/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday I&amp;rsquo;ve released the first official stable version of my imagemap_wizard extension (TER). I though that&amp;rsquo;s a good moment to review the introduction text on the project-homepage and that&amp;rsquo;s how it looks like - forge.typo3.org/projects/show/extension-imagemap_wizard
Especially due to the missing/broken TER download counter I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure whether the work was worth it. I hope some marketing and the given information about all the cool featutes is enough for newbees and TYPO3 pro&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 crawler extension</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/09/typo3-crawler-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 07:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/09/typo3-crawler-extension/</guid>
      <description>Cool thing just happend after a couple of months we finally released the new version of the famous crawler extension. Read more on forge,typo3.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 extensions ....</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/typo3-extensions-..../</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 19:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/07/typo3-extensions-..../</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently within the preparation for some exams therefore my day&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t very fancy at all - and that&amp;rsquo;s why I just decided to introduce some TYPO3 extensions - especially TYPO3 extensions where I&amp;rsquo;m somehow involved ;)
The mentioned extensions are all created by AOEmedia or in cooperation with AOEmedia, they&amp;rsquo;re actively maintained and they work within regular TYPO3 environments with all TYPO3 features -lot&amp;rsquo;s of other extensions don&amp;rsquo;t support l10n and workspaces - ours do ;) Please use the mentioned pages on forge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>disable TemplaVoila new page wizard</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/disable-templavoila-new-page-wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 16:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/disable-templavoila-new-page-wizard/</guid>
      <description>TemplaVoila&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;new page wizard&amp;rdquo; is a pretty cool featue - at least if your page templates have a thumbnail and a description. If your &amp;ldquo;new page wizard&amp;rdquo; look like the image on the right you might consider to turn it of.
That&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy just paste this into the Page TSConfig of your rootpage and you&amp;rsquo;re done: mod.web_list.newPageWiz.overrideWithExtension &amp;gt; Now you might wonder how TemplaVoila knows what template it should use to render the page - but due to the TV&amp;rsquo;s default behaviour to inherit the page-template this should not be a problem if there&amp;rsquo;s at least a TemplaVoila page template assigned for your root-page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 nerds community- share your location!</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-nerds-community--share-your-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2009 14:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-nerds-community--share-your-location/</guid>
      <description>Georg just published a nice littel mashup where you can place a pin on a Google-Map - It&amp;rsquo;s meant to show where the TYPO3 community is located and how big it is. It seems that already lot&amp;rsquo;s of people placed their pins - so what you&amp;rsquo;re waiting for? (click)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 extensions from Subversion</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-extensions-from-subversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 11:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/06/typo3-extensions-from-subversion/</guid>
      <description>[(/uploads/2009/06/svn2t3x-snap.png)
From time to time it&amp;rsquo;s really buggin me that some &amp;ldquo;TYPO3 integrators&amp;rdquo; don&amp;rsquo;t have PHP skills. And since Subversion is imho the most important tool within groups of developers, their missing PHP skills are a real downside because they can&amp;rsquo;t use the newest extension version directly out of the Subversion repository. Therefore I decided to create a handy little tool which enables to generate TYPO3 .t3x extension-files from any Subversion repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 templavoila rtfm</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/typo3-templavoila-rtfm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 21:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/05/typo3-templavoila-rtfm/</guid>
      <description>Dmitry and Steffen included some of the AOE guys (including me) into the TemplaVoila team and we all try to contribute into the project from now on. Therefore I just checked the Unit-tests for TemplaVoila and tried to find a way how to improve them in the future and somewhere within the tx_templavoila_api -Class I found the PageTS key &amp;ldquo;tx_templavoila.storagePid&amp;rdquo;. That seems to be some kind of nice workaround for everyone who&amp;rsquo;s not interested to mess up the TYPO3 general record storage page with the TemplaVoila DS/TO storage-folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>webdesign and stuff that came along my way today</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2009/04/webdesign-and-stuff-that-came-along-my-way-today/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine recommended this URL in regards to one topic which I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on: Designing Drop-Down Menus: Examples and Best Practices . This article about how to use Drop-Down menus within the navigation, including some DOs and some DONTs, is a very nice summary for anyone who creates designs with these elements.
After I scanned that article, I found another one which will be my default answer in the future whenever clients or coworkers ask strange questions about features and designs: 9 Common Usability Mistakes In Web Design | How-To | Smashing Magazine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TYPO3 API...</title>
      <link>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/typo3-api.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//blog.tolleiv.de/2008/05/typo3-api.../</guid>
      <description>The API documentation on typo3.org is not very up-to-date, but the typo3-unleashed.net guys just provided some links to the API documentation of the current TYPO3 versions - http://www.typo3-unleashed.net/api_online.html - thanks a lot :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>